翻译，压制：旋火
视频来源：youtu.be/L5lrIAvWB2A
→下一代欧洲运载火箭
注：Ariane音译名阿丽亚娜
Trucks arrive with the first and second stage of Ariane 6
卡车运来了Ariane 6的一级和二级
at the Launcher assembly building in Kourou
在库鲁的火箭组装厂房
Here both stages are assembled horizontally
在这里 两个分级将被水平组装
before being transported to the mobile gantry for further integration.
之后将运到大型移动台架 进行进一步整合
This is the process each Ariane 6 will go through
这是每个Ariane 6都会经历的过程
This simplifies the preparation process
这简化了准备过程
just as in a car factory assembly line
就像在车厂装配线上一样
and soon it will be into practice at Europe's spaceport
在欧洲航天港 这将很快被投入实用
Here the construction of the new launch base for Ariane 6
这是为Ariane 6建造的新发射基地
is in its finalisation phase
即将完工
On one side the Launcher assembly building
一边是火箭组装厂房
and then the launch pad itself
另一边则是发射场
with the big mobile gantry
以及一个大型移动台架
Here Ariane 6's boosters and fairing with payloads will be fitted
在这里 Ariane 6的助推器和带有整流罩的有效载荷将会被安装上
Ariane 6 facilities are taking shape
Ariane 6的设施正在逐渐成形
Europe's future launchers are becoming reality
欧洲未来的运载火箭将成为现实
注：太空运输总监
So first the Ariane 6 the development go full speed ahead
像这样 Ariane 6的开发正在全速开展
and now the industry has started the production of the first 14 launchers of Ariane 6
现在整个产业已经开始生产首批14枚Ariane 6运载火箭
in addition to the maiden flight
不包括首飞的那枚
So 15 launchers in production today
所以现在总共有15枚正在生产
注：Vega C音译名为维加
On Vega C side all engines are tested and
对于Vega C那边 所有发动机都测试了
we had the test of the Zefiro 40
包括Zefiro 40火箭发动机
which was the last engine test
已经是最终的发动机测试了
and now we are really on the final path
现在可以说是到了最终阶段了
towards the maiden flight of Vega C as well
对Vega C的首航而言也是如此
Vega C is the new and enhanced version of Europe's lightweight launcher Vega
Vega C是欧洲小型运载火箭Vega的全新加强版本
It will allow for an increased and versatile payload capacity from Kourou
它将使库鲁的多种有效载荷能力得到提高
In parallel
与此同时
ESA is supporting the development of a structure to launch multiple satellites
欧空局也在支持并开发一种能发射多颗卫星的结构
called Small Spacecraft Mission Service
叫做小型航天器任务服务
This dispenser allows more than a dozen small satellites
这种分配器允许超过12颗卫星
to be launched under the fairing of Vega and then Vega C
在Vega和Vega C的整流罩中一起被发射
which will soon launch from Kourou for the first time
很快将在库鲁进行首次发射
We will have a proof of concept flight on Vega
我们将在Vega上进行概念验证飞行
allowing to launch light satellites
使之能够发射小卫星
a big number of small satellites
很多小卫星
and we are already now preparing the same for Vega C and Ariane 6
我们现在也准备在Vega C和Ariane 6上做同样的事情
So all our European launchers which are in development today
现在所有我们开发中的欧洲运载火箭
will have the capacity to offer a launch of a number of small satellites
都会有能力一次发射多个小卫星
light satellites
或者说是轻型卫星
It's a real market enhancement
这将拓展我们的市场
注：可翻译为乘空者(太空Rider)
Another project for ESA is Space Rider
另外一个欧空局的项目是Space Rider
It is the continuation of the Intermediate eXperimental Vehicle, IXV
这是过渡试验飞行器(IXV)的延续项目
the successful mission that flew in February 2015
IXV在2015年2月成功发射并飞行
Space Rider is an unmanned orbital vehicle
Space Rider是一个无人轨道飞行器
that should provide Europe with its first
应该能给欧洲带来其首个
operational reusable space transportation system
可重复使用的太空运输系统
It will be able to return from space
它能从太空返回
and will allow for experiments in microgravity
还可以进行微重力实验
in-orbit validation of technologies
在轨技术验证
deployment of small satellites
部署小卫星
注：类似X-37B和某不可描述
and might even be used for Earth observation applications
甚至还能用于地球观测应用
or Servicing missions
或者维修任务
We have today the access to space component
现在我们有能力进入太空
which is covered through Ariane 6 and Vega C
这由Ariane 6和Vega C来保障
we are developing at ESA STS space transportation also propulsion elements
我们正在为欧空局开发太空运输系统及其推进系统
engines for transport in space
用于太空运输的发动机
and with Space Rider we have an operational capability
而Space Rider会给我们这项能力
注：20191129的消息，决定继续开发，75%的钱由意大利出，最快2022年发射
spacenews.com/italy-satisfied-with-outcome-of-esa-ministerial
which will have to be decided in Seville end of the year
我们将在今年(2019年)晚些时候在塞维利亚作出决定
for returning from space on Earth
也就是从太空返回地球的能力
While the ministerial conference in Seville
以后在塞维利亚举行的部长级会议
will decide on the further development of Space Rider
将会决定未来Space Rider的进一步开发
注：从左到右：Soyuz ST，Ariane 5，Vega
Today
现在
with its range of launch vehicles
根据运载火箭的发射能力
Europe is already able to launch any type of satellite into any orbit
欧洲已经能将任何类型的卫星发射到任何轨道
注：指用Vega C发射Space Rider
The new portfolio under development
新的组合正在开发
aims to further secure this approach on the commercial launcher market
旨在进一步确保欧洲在商业发射市场上的地位
and at the same time
而与此同时
ensures Europe's independent access to space in the future.
保障将来欧洲独立自主进入太空的能力